Neural networks do a lot of math with a lot of data.
神经网络可以对大量数据执行大量运算
But before we can start designing those networks
但是在自己开始设计这些网络
ourselves, and making sure all that math is set up correctly,
并正确设定了相关数学公式之前
we first need to understand how we represent that data.
我们首先需要了解如何表示这些数据
Specifically, we need to think about the shapes data can have.
具体而言 我们需要思考数据可能具备的分布形状
For example, we might have a single number, representing
例如 可能有一个数字
a person's height in centimeters,
表示人的身高（厘米）
or a list of numbers representing
或者有一系列的数字
various features of that person, like height, weight, and age.
表示此人的各种特征 例如身高 体重和年龄
Or maybe we have an image of that person
或者有一张关于此人的图片
and represent it as a grid, with rows and columns
它由某种网格构成 每个位置都是
of individual pixels.
一个像素
And one possible way to represent a single pixel
表示该图片中单个像素的一种方法是
in that image might use three numbers,
使用三个数字
one for each of the red, blue, and green color channels.
分别表示红色 蓝色和绿色通道的值
We describe these different shapes
我们用它们的纬度的数量
of data in terms of their number of dimensions.
来描述各种数据形状
First, we have the smallest, simplest shape, a single value,
首先是最小 最简单的形状 即单个值
like 1, 2.4, or negative 0.3.
例如 1 2.4 或 -0.3
These are called scalars.
这些叫做标量
We see that scalars.
我们可以看出
Have zero dimensions.
标量的维度为零
It's impossible to visualize zero dimensions,
我们无法可视化零维度
but just go with it.
但是不用管
That's how scalars are defined.
标量就是这么定义的
So from the examples before, a person's height
所以 在之前的例子中
would be a scalar and have a zero-dimensional shape.
人的身高是标量 形状是零维度
Then, there are lists of values called vectors.
此外 还有由一列数据构成的数 叫做向量
There are two types, row vectors and column vectors.
向量包括两种类型 行向量和列向量
They can store the same things.
它们可以存储相同的内容
But conceptually, you would think of a row vector
但抽象地想 你可以将行向量
like this, 1, 2, 3, ordered horizontally from left
想象成从左到右水平排列的 [1 2 3]
to right, and a column vector like this, 1, 2, 3, ordered
将列向量看做从上到下排列的
vertically from top to bottom.
[1 2 3]
The reason to use one type of vector over the other
使用哪一种向量
is sometimes just a personal preference.
通常只是个人喜好问题
But other times, the shape actually
但是有时候 向量的形状
affects the math you can do.
会影响到数学运算（的形式）
Either way, a vector is said to have one dimension, which
但不管怎么说 向量是一维的量
we call its length.
我们称其为长度
So each of these two vectors has a length of 3.
所以这两个向量的长度都为 3
Our list from before, with a person's height, weight,
我们之前的列表 关于一个人的身高
and age, could be stored as a vector.
体重和年龄 可以存储为向量
Next up, we have matrices.
接着是矩阵
A matrix is a two-dimensional grid of values.
矩阵是二维的值
We describe the shape of a matrix
我们用行数和列数
in terms of its numbers of rows and columns.
来描述矩阵的形状
So if you had these two rows of data, 1, 2, 3, and 4, 5, 6,
如果有这两行数据 [1 2 3] 和 [4 5 6]
that's two rows and three columns.
则是两行及三列
So we'd say it's a 2 by 3 matrix.
我们称其为 2 x 3 的矩阵
If you had a single number for each pixel of an image,
如果图片中的每个像素有一个数字
then you could store those pixel values in a matrix.
那么可以将这些像素值存储到矩阵中
Finally, there are things called tensors.
最后是张量
You'll hear this term a lot in this course.
你将在这门课程中经常听到张量一词
Because you'll spend quite a bit of time
因为你将花大量时间
using a software library called TensorFlow,
使用一种叫做 TensorFlow 的软件库
and it deals with all its data in the form of tensors.
该库的所有数据都是张量形式
The term tensor can refer to any n-dimensional collection
张量可以指任何 n 维的
of values.
值集合
So a scalar is a zero-dimensional tensor;
总结一下 标量是零维张量
a vector is a one-dimensional tensor;
向量是一维张量
a matrix is a two-dimensional tensor;
矩阵是二维张量
and anything larger than two dimensions,
任何大于二维的对象
we just call it tensor.
我们就称为张量
The problem is higher dimensional data
问题是 更高维度的数据
can be difficult to visualize.
难以可视化
For three dimensions, you might picture a stack of matrices.
对于三维 你可以想象成矩阵堆栈
But you could just as easily picture a list of matrices,
但是也可以想象成矩阵列表
or a matrix of vectors.
或向量矩阵
And for four dimensions, you might think of a matrix
对于四维 可以想象成一种矩阵
where each of its entries is itself
其中每个项目本身
a matrix, or maybe a list or stack
都是一个矩阵 或一个矩阵列表的列表
of stacks of matrices, or maybe even something else.
或者还可以是其他形式
And it just keeps getting more complicated
随着维度的增多
as the number of dimensions goes up.
越来越复杂
The important thing to remember is
要记住的一点是
that even if you have trouble imagining
即使很难想象
how the data is arranged, you can probably
数据是如何组织的 我们依然能
still make the math work.
对它们进行数学进行运算
So back to our earlier examples, if we
回到之前的示例
had a separate value for each color channel
如果图片每个像素的每个颜色通道
of each pixel of an image, we could
都有一个单独的值
store those as a three-dimensional tensor
我们可以将这些值存储为三维张量
with separate planes for red, green, and blue values.
并用单独的平面表示红色 绿色和蓝色值
For these lessons, we'll mostly talk in terms
在接下来的几节课中
of scalars and matrices.
我们将主要讲解标量和矩阵
When we use vectors, we'll just think of them as matrices, too,
对于向量 我们可以将其看做矩阵
where one of their dimensions is size 1.
其中一个维度的大小是 1
For example, when considering these length
例如 对于之前这些
three vectors from earlier, we would
长度为 3 的向量
say this row vector is a 1 by 3 matrix.
可以将这个行向量看做 1 x 3 的矩阵
And this column actor is a 3 by 1 matrix.
将这个列向量看做 3 x 1 的矩阵
We'll also sometimes need to refer to individual elements
我们有时候还需要指代矩阵中的
inside of matrix.
某个特定元素（数）
We do that using its index, which is its row then column.
我们通过索引（即行和列位置）进行指代
So if this matrix were named A, its values
如果这个矩阵称为 A
are located at these indices.
则它各个位置的数可以被这样指代
The indices of the locations in the first row are A 1 1, A 1 2,
第一行的索引是 a11 a12
and A 1 3.
和 a13
The locations in the second row are at indices A 2 1, A 2 2,
第二行的索引是 a21 a22
and A 2 3, and so on.
和 a23 等等
So we'd say the value at A 3 2 is 8.
所以 a32 的值是 8
One last thing I should mention.
最后提醒下
In math books, things you read online, even most of the things
在数学课本及网上资料中
you read in this class, indices usually
甚至这节课的大部分内容中
start at 1, like I've shown here.
索引通常都从 1 开始 例如这里所显示的
See how the first row is row 1 and the first column
第一行从 1 开始
is column 1?
第一列也从 1 开始
Counting from one makes perfect sense.
从 1 开始数很合理
But in programming languages, it's more common for indices
但是在编程语言中 索引通常
to start at 0, which looks like this.
都是从 0 开始 就像这样
All the indices are just one less than you might expect.
所有索引都比你认为的小 1
So in code, instead of that 8 being at index A 3 2,
所以在代码中 8 的索引不是 a32
we'd say it's at index A 2 1.
而是 a21
If you've got some experience writing software,
如果你有编程经验的话
you're probably already used to this,
或许已经习惯这种索引表示方法
so just keep in mind that most written material is
只需记住 大部分的书面材料
indexed from 1.
索引都从 1 开始
But if you're new to programming,
但是如果你是编程新手的话
it's almost certainly going to take you some time
肯定需要一些时间
to get used to counting from 0.
才能习惯于从 0 开始这种表示方法